Diane and Carrie, how much time do you usually spend choosing and
Diane 和 Carrie 你们一般会耗费多少时间
validating metrics, like we talked about in this lesson?
选择确认指标 像我们在本课中提及的这些？
As opposed to, say, running the experiment, or analyzing the results?
对比运行实验或分析结果所用的时间？
>> So, what I would say is that, for a lot of the analysts that I've worked
这么说 在 Google 合作过的分析师
with at Google, we spend the majority of our time actually coming up with,
比起评估实验本身
validating, and choosing metrics to actually use in evaluation.
我们绝大部分的时间都耗费在提出、
As opposed to evaluating the experiments themselves.
确认、选择评估使用的指标上
>> Especially validating metrics.
尤其是验证指标
A lot of people like to throw out product metrics that all seem perfectly
很多人喜欢向我们随意提出一些产品指标
reasonable.
看着都很合理的样子
For example, the number of times a particular search term shows up
举个例子 你在做特定领域 比如旅游市场营销的时候
when you're running a marketing campaign for a particular area like travel.
某个搜索词出现的次数
Now this seems like a perfectly reasonably thing to track.
看着好像非常合理
But you really don't know how your site is actually going to respond.
但你真的不知道网站会如何回应
And so sometimes you end up with spurious results if you haven't
而你之前如果没有使用过这个指标
used the metric before.
最后你可能得到错误的结果
Oh, it went up 100, right?
最后结果可能是 100
Or you end up with no results at all.
或者根本没有结果
It didn't move at all, and you have no idea if that's normal or
根本没什么进展 你都不知道这个是正常的
if that's something you should be concerned about.
或者是你需要特别注意的
>> Okay. Do you have any stories about things
那你们有没有什么
that have gone wrong.
出错的经验
>> Sure. Where would you like to start?
当然有 你想从哪里开始？
>> How about data capture and metric definition?
不如说说数据采集和指标定义？
>> So one story I like to tell is about click-through rate.
我想说的一个就是点击率
So back in 2006,
回到 2006 年
you know, we were running lots of different experiments and everyone was
你知道我们一直在运行各种不同的实验
using click-through rate to measure the user experience of their test.
大家都使用点击率来测量用户体验
Now, you're like, how hard can it be to calculate click-through rate?
但是 你会觉得 计算点击率能有多困难？
I mean, really.
但我是说真的
It's clicks divided by impressions or page views.
要用点击率除以显示或网页浏览量
Well this is the problem.
好了 问题来了
Talking about impressions or page views?
那是显示还是网页浏览？
The first page of the search results or all the next pages?
是搜索结果第一页 还是所有页？
Are you doing it in the US only or globally?
只针对美国 还是针对全球？
Are you removing spam or are you not removing spam?
你会去掉 spam 或不去掉？
I mean, you name it, we had to decide every single one of those questions.
不管怎么样 你得决定每一个小小的问题
And so whenever someone was looking at experiment the first question was not
所以当我们第一次看到这个实验的时候 第一个问题不是说
oh, well how does this result compare to this other experiment?
这个结果与其他实验结果对比如何？
The first question was how did you compute six through eight again?
第一个问题是你能再说一下你是怎么计算点击率的么
Which, which, which definition did you use?
你用的是哪个定义？
Just being able to standardize the definition was really important towards
要能够在完全不同的层次上开始对话
just being able to start the conversation at a whole different level.
非常重要的一点是能够将定义标准化
>> Latency, which we’ve been talking about a lot, or
延迟 之前我们也谈论过不少了
how long it takes a page to load is another good example.
或者说载入页面需要多长时间 这个也是个好例子
Now when you think about it you don’t really sit next to the user and
因为你不是坐在用户旁边
measure this.
测量这个
You’re looking in a whole bunch of events and
你需要查看大量的事件
pings back that happen and hand offs.
pingsback 以及切换
So for example, when does the first byte load?
比如说 什么时间载入的第一个字节
How did you measure that?
你如何测量到的？
When you say how long does it take the page to load,
你在说页面载入需要多少时间
are you talking about when the first byte loads or when the last byte loads?
是指什么时候载入第一个字节或什么时候载入最后一个字节？
And so, it really becomes a discussion about agreeing on what you're
所以就变成了
actually going to technically measure in this metric.
在这个指标下你技术上测量什么内容的讨论了
And not a discussion about, hey, did we improve our latency here or not?
而不是说 我们是否有改善我们的延迟时间
>> Wow, so how about sensitivity and robustness?
那 敏感性和稳健性呢
Any stories about those?
有没有这方面的经验可分享？
>> Well, latency is another good example of those,
延迟时间也是一个好的例子
because latency tends to be really lumpy.
因为它真的有非常多的问题
And you look at the mean, and it doesn't move at all.
你看看平均值 发现没有任何进展
And part of the reason is that you have users who have very different
有部分原因可能是你的用户
connection speeds.
连接速度有很大差别
So you have a bunch of people who have super fast speeds.
可能有些人连接速度超快
You have people who have slow speeds.
有的速度很慢
You have people who have some kind of problem on their computer,
有的电脑有某些问题
maybe they have an old browser.
可能浏览器太旧
And so these signals that you're getting cause these sort of lumpiness in
这些都可能引起你的分布
the distribution.
呈现团块结构
So you really want to move away from using something like the mean and
所以你要停止使用平均值
start looking at well, do I have to use a higher percentile?
看看是否需要使用更高的百分位数
Because I can't get the mean to move at all.
因为用平均值的话 我没法得到任何进展
One change effects the people who have the fast connections, and
一个变更会影响快速连接的用户
one change effects the people who have the slow connections, and
一个变更影响连接速度慢的用户
I can't get any sort of central measure.
我无法测量中间的位置
So we spent a lot of time with latency, looking for
所以我们用很多时间考虑延迟
the right higher percentile metric, that we could actually get to move,
寻找我们可以使用的更高的百分位数指标
when we knew we'd done something that was positive for the latency experience.
这样当我们做了一些在延迟体验上的正面改变的时候 我们可以知道
>> Another example is from search.
另外一个例子是搜索
Now in search, we love the metric tasks per user per day.
在搜索中 我们喜欢用每天每个用户的任务量这个指标
Now, the problem with task per user per day is not that it's a bad metric,
而每天每个用户的任务量的问题是 它不是一个不好的指标
it's that it's a very stable metric.
它是个很稳定的指标
And what that basically means is that, for
也就是说
just about any experiment you weren't changing that metric.
在任何实验中 你都不会改变这个指标
And in fact, if you did actually measure a change in task per user per day,
如果你在每日每个用户的任务量中测量到了变化
it was probably a sign that you screwed up your experiment
这可能是说明你搞砸了实验
as opposed to actually changing the metric.
而不是改变了这个指标
Now, it's worth noting that even as a business metric,
即便作为一个业务指标 它也没什么价值
task per user per day has a bunch of definition issues,
每日每个用户的任务量有很多定义上的问题
like what time period actually makes the most sense.
比如选择怎样的一个时间区间
Do you care about per day, or per week?
你是在意每一天还是每一周的指标？
I mean, just think about your own search habits.
想想自己的搜索习惯
You probably search a couple of times per week, or
我可能每周或者每两周
even a two week period, as opposed to on an every day basis.
搜索几次 而不是每天
Now, one of the things to, sort of, think about as you're, sort of,
所以在定义指标时 你需要做的一件事
defining metrics is, do your metrics have a big weekly variability?
是考虑你的指标在一周的时间内是否有很强的差异性？
Businesses tend to love, like, these 30 day metrics, but
在商业角度上 一般很喜欢 30 天这个指标
if your if your site has a bunch of weekly variability,
但如果你的网站有每周的差异性
28 days might make way more sense than 30 days.
28 天可能会比 30 天更合理
>> Yeah.
对的
I mean, there's a certain amount of judgment that you have to apply at
在过程的一开始
the beginning of this process,
你会必须要做出一些判断
but you also really have to try these things out.
但是你真的需要尝试
Because you actually won't think of all those types of effects.
因为你不可能考虑到所有类型的效应
And when you try it, you'll suddenly see something really strange.
你在尝试的时候 会突然发现一些很奇怪的东西
>> I mean, as we talked about,
像我们之前谈到过的
the key thing is that you're actually building intuition.
关键在于你要开发出自己的直觉
You have to understand your data, your system.
你要了解数据、系统
You have to work with your engineers to understand the nuances
你需要和工程师合作了解
about how data is actually being captured.
数据采集的细节
>> Wow! Interesting.
真有意思